Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Muiznieks Residence, Kalamazoo, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1979
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on three pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches, and one sheet of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of spiral notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
  - University of Iowa College of Law Building, Iowa City, Iowa, 1979-1986
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketches on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Brown and black ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on steno pad paper with notation "Jamaica Inn, Key Biscayne," on illustration board, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, 02/21/1980; Blue ink sketches on two pieces of steno pad paper with notation "Sandbar, Key Biscayne," 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, 01/18/1984; Ink sketch with notations on reverse side of "Butler Design Competition" poster, initialed, 15-3/4x20-3/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Blue and brown ink sketches on three sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 06/26/1986; Ink sketches on two sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches, one dated (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on seven sheets of spiral notebook paper, one signed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Light Shelf Study], untitled, Brown ink sketches on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
      - Design Development Drawings
        - Presentation Floor Plans and Axonometric Drawings, Four drawings with colored pantone, 22-1/2x18 to 23-1/2x20 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
  - Cathedral of the Most Blessed Sacrament Renovation, Detroit, Michigan, 1980-2002
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Article, 2000 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Purple crayon sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 16-3/4x23-1/4 & 17-1/4x31 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Black, brown and blue ink sketches on four sheets of spiral notebook paper, signed, 8-1/2x11 inches, one dated 1982 (Map-case 4, Folder 1)
  - Ferguson Residence (Villa Ginny), Kalamazoo, Michigan, 1980-1983
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, 10/29/1980; Green ink sketch on steno pad paper drawn in an airplane, with notation "over Colorado," 6x9 inches, 8x10-inch black-and-white photographic print, and 3-1/2x5-inch negative (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Brown and black ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x25-1/2 inches, 8x10-inch black-and-white photographic print, and 3-1/2x5-inch negative (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Green, brown and blue ink sketches on one sheet of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches, and three sheets of tracing paper, 12x18 to 12x31 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketches of] Lower Floor and Upper Level, Brown and black ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x9-1/4 & 12x12 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Swedish architectural magazine proof sheet with copies of sketches of Ferguson Residence, State of Wisconsin Office Building and University of Iowa College of Law Building, 7x10-1/2 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled. Ink sketches on two sheets of spiral notebook paper, signed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
        - Conceptual Sketches, Black, brown and green ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x9-1/2 to 12x26 inches
          - Typical Wall, 03/18/1981; 03/19/1981; 2 drawings (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Roof Framing., 03/19/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Plane at Cantilever., 03/19/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Wall at Kitchen, Lower Floor., 03/19/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Wall at Breakfast Nook., 03/19/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Laundry and Pantry., 03/20/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Third Level Plan., 03/20/1981 (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Roof Framing and Venting., Undated (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
          - Untitled Sketches, undated; 2 drawings (Map-case 4, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University Uris Library Addition, Ithaca, New York, 1980-1982
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Site Plan], untitled, Green ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x23 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x18 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Brown and blue ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x14-1/2 to 12x20 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
  - Baldwin Public Library Addition, Birmingham, Michigan, 1980-1983
    - Project Files
      - Specifications and Addenda #1 and #2. Microfilm prints and 5/29/81, 05/22/1981 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1980-1991 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Conceptual Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Conceptual Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketches on three sheets of spiral notebook paper, two initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
      - Schematic Design Sketches
        - [Sections], untitled., 1980; undated; Blue ink sketches on two sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
  - Chapel and Educational Facility, U. S. Army, Camp Wildflecken, Germany, 1980-1983
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Journal Article, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 12/07/1980; Ink sketches on two sides of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on five sheets of "Steigenberger Reservation Service" memo pad paper, 3-1/4x5-1/2 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled and12/8/80, undated; Ink sketches on two sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
        - [Roof, Window and Wall Details], most untitled, Brown, black and blue ink sketches on twelve sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 3)
  - St. Paul's Latvian Church, Redford, Michigan, 1980
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Stained Glass Window Studies], untitled, Marker coloring on four electrostatic prints, signed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 4)
        - [Section], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on blue-line print, 16-1/2x24 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 4)
        - [Plan and Section], untitled, Pencil drawing on sepia print, 32x36 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 4)
  - St. Peter's Lutheran Church, Columbus, Indiana, 1980-1988
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, . Blue ink sketch on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of steno pad paper and program notes on one sheet of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches, and two sheets of tracing paper, 12x19 & 12x27 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x19 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Green ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x19 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on tracing paper, 18x17 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 5)
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and green ink sketches on eighteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x12-3/4 to 24x31-3/4 inches, four initialed and dated 1984 (Map-case 4, Folder 6)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 8-1/4x16-1/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 6)
      - Conceptual Sketches of Roof and Steeple. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Black ink sketch on tracing paper, 24x32 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Black and blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 24x33 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x31-3/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, 1984; Ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed, 12x21-1/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Roof Studies], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches with gray marker coloring on six sheets of tracing paper, 12x18-3/4 to 18x30 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Steeple], untitled, Blue ink sketches with purple marker coloring on tracing paper, 18x27 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
      - Schematic Design Drawings of Roof and Steeple., Undated
        - [Roof and Steeple Section Study], untitled, Black and green ink and red pencil sketch on black-line print, 26-1/2x25 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Roof and Steeple Section], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 24x17-1/2 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
        - [Steeple Section], untitled, Green marker coloring on black-line print, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 7)
      - Conceptual Sketches of Millwork. Undated, except as noted
        - [Eternal Flame], untitled, Blue and brown ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x29 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Eternal Flame], untitled, Brown ink and pencil sketches on tracing paper, 12x23-3/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Entrance Door Elevation], untitled, 02/03/1986; Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x24-1/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Entrance Door Elevation], untitled., undated; 02/03/1986; Brown, blue and black ink sketches on seven sheets of tracing paper, 12x16-1/4 to 12x20 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Pew], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x12 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Pew], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x11 to 12x12 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Pew], untitled, Blue ink sketch on electrostatic print of "New Holland Church Furniture" brochure, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Entrance Door Elevations], untitled, Pencil and colored pencil drawings on three sheets of tracing paper, 12-1/2x18 to 12x25 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 8)
        - [Pulpit], untitled, Brown and blue ink sketches on eight sheets of tracing paper, 9x12 to 12x15-1/2 inches, and one piece of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 9)
        - [Building Sign], untitled, Blue ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x20-3/4 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 9)
        - [Altar Table], untitled, Black, blue and green ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, 12x11-1/2 to 12x18 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 9)
        - [Altar Rail], untitled, Blue ink sketches on six sheets of tracing paper, 12x10-1/2 to 12x14 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 9)
        - [Communion Cart], untitled, Blue ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x7-3/4 to 12x12-1/2 inches (Map-case 4, Folder 9)
  - University of Nebraska, Wick Alumni Center Competition, Lincoln, Nebraska (unbuilt project), 1981
    - Project Files
      - Journal Article, March 1983 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on two sides of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
        - [Site and Floor Plans], untitled, Red crayon and black, brown and green ink sketches on eighteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x16 to 24x36 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
      - Schematic Design Drawings. Red pencil, pencil and ink sketches and drawings on black-line prints, 24x36 inches, except as noted, undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
        - Site Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Drawings on two prints (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
        - [Elevations], untitled, Drawings on four prints, one 18x36 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 1)
  - State of Wisconsin Office Building, Green Bay, Wisconsin, 1981-1983
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, 03/10/1981; Blue ink sketches on two pages of letter from William Schuman, Chairman, The MacDowell Colony, including Gunnar Birkerts' notation, "Dinner Tom Bu" [Buechner, Director of Corning Museum of Glass], 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed, 21x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sides of "St. Moritz on-the-Park" envelope, with notations, 4x7-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on steno pad paper with notations, 6x9 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and black ink sketches on graph paper with notations, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sides of "Center for Creative Studies Student Exhibition" announcement, 10x7 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on six pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Green, blue, brown and black ink and black crayon sketches on twenty sheets of tracing paper, 12x15 to 24x46 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Drawing], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 15x21 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 2)
  - Anchorage Library Competition, Anchorage, Alaska (unbuilt project), 1981
    - Project Files
      - Journal Article, March 1983 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, signed, 12x26-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Blue, green and brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x34 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled., circa 1984; Print on announcement of "Gunnar Birkerts: Brainwaves, Sketches, Drawings, Projects and Buildings" Exhibition, Toronto, 7-1/2x8-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 06/23/1981; Red, blue, green and brown ink sketches on thirteen sheets of tracing paper, 12x15 to 18x38 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
      - Presentation Drawings, undated; Electrostatic prints on mylar, except as noted, 20-3/4x20 inches
        - Photographic Print of Building Model (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Phase One Site Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Phase Two Site Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Ground Floor Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Second Floor Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Third Floor Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Fourth Floor Plan (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Sections Looking East and South (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - Phase Two Floor Plans (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
  - University of Michigan Law Library Rare Book Room, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1982
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled. Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x29-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - Level 1 Floor Plan, Blue ink and colored pencil drawing on electrostatic print, 17-3/4x24-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - [Elevation], untitled, Pencil-on-vellum drawing, 10-1/2x15 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
        - [Floor Plan], untitled, Red pencil drawing on electrostatic print, 18x28-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 3)
  - IBM Lahser Road Facility, Southfield, Michigan, 1982
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints, 04/12/1982 (Box 10)
  - University of Michigan Knoxville World's Fair Charette, Knoxville, Tennessee (unbuilt project), 1982
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Post-World's Fair Riverside Development Project Drawings
        - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
          - [Site Plan], untitled, Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 12-1/4x22-1/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
          - [Site Plan], untitled, Black crayon sketch with crayon coloring on tracing paper, 18x39 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
          - [Site Plan], untitled, Colored pencil and crayon drawing and coloring on blue-line print, 19x40-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
          - Site Plan [Presentation Drawing], Black and white photographic print of ink drawing on illustration board, 13x29-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
  - Woodbranch Energy Plaza, Houston, Texas (unbuilt project), 1982
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Green ink sketches on steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on shirt cardboard, 8x12-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Black, green and red ink and pencil sketch on black-line print of site plan, 20-3/4x31-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue, purple, brown, green and black ink sketches on six sheets of tracing paper, 12x31-1/2 to 21x43-1/4 inches, and one blue-line print, 18-1/4x48 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 08/06/1981; Blue, brown and black ink sketches on twelve sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketch], untitled, 05/24/1983; Ink sketch on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on three sheets of "Warwick Post Oak Hotel" note paper, 4x6 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on one sheet of tracing paper, 10-1/2x12 inches, one sheet of white paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one sheet of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and red ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x12-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Lifestyle Enhancement Center Floor Plan], untitled, Green and red pencil drawing on vellum, 17x22 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 4)
  - ParkCenter, Houston, Texas (unbuilt project), 1983
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x23 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue ink sketch on memo pad paper, initialed, 4x6 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled. undated, 05/29/1983; 05/30/1983; Blue ink sketches on five pieces of tracing paper, 12x26 to 12x40 inches, two initialed and dated 5/29/83 and one initialed and dated 5/30/83 (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, 10-3/4x12 to 12x14-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
  - Holtzman & Silverman Office Building, Southfield, Michigan, 1983-1989
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Blue, black and green ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, initialed, 12x21-3/4 & 12x23-1/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Plan], untitled, Pencil and red pencil drawings on two sheets of vellum, initialed, 15x17-1/4 & 13-1/4x25 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 5)
  - IBM Beecher Road Facility, Flint, Michigan, 1984-1985
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Bid Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints, 07/16/1984 (Box 10)
  - Domino's Farms Master Plan, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1984
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Early Round Site Studies
        - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
          - [Early Sketches], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on tracing paper, 18x19-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 6)
          - [Early Sketch], untitled, Black ink and blue crayon sketch on tracing paper, 13x18 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 6)
          - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 02/01/1984; Black, blue and brown ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, 11-1/2x12 to 17x24 inches, and two sheets of notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, one initialed and dated 2/1/84 (Map-case 5, Folder 6)
        - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
          - [Site Plan], untitled, One pencil and red pencil drawing on vellum, 13x24-1/4 inches, and one electrostatic print with green and brown pencil coloring, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 6)
      - Site Studies with Linear and Natural Elements
        - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
          - [Sketch], untitled, Red ink sketches on white spiral notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
          - [Sketches], untitled, undated; 01/27/1986; Black, blue, green and red ink sketches on ten sheets of tracing paper, 12x13-1/4 to 18x25 inches, one initialed and dated 1/27/86 (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
          - [Sketches], untitled, Red ink sketches on the reverse of two sheets of electrostatic print paper, one with notations, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
        - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
          - [Site Plan], untitled, Colored ink and crayon drawings on two black-line prints, 11x24 & 12x36-3/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
          - [Site Plan], untitled., Pencil and crayon drawing and sketch on vellum, initialed, 12x25-1/4 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
        - "Development of Domino Farms Concepts and Manifestations," Poster announcing public lecture by Gunnar Birkerts, 11/12/1984; 17x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 7)
      - Site Studies with Tower
        - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
          - [Sketch], untitled, Black ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x20-1/2 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 8)
          - [Sketches], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on eight sheets of tracing paper, 8-3/4x12 to 18x33-3/4 inches, and one sheet of white paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 5, Folder 8)
  - Domino's Pizza, Inc. Headquarters, Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1984-1998
    - Project Files
      - Monaghan's and Birkerts' Meeting Notes (Box 9)
      - Newspaper and Journal Articles Regarding Headquarters and Tower, 1984-2002 (Box 9)
      - Press Releases, 1986-1989 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 9)
      - Gunnar Birkerts & Associates On-Site Office Guest Book, with celebrity signatures, 11/88-10/90 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings